<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>opendtect on WM Seismic Solutions</title>
    <link>https://waynegm.github.io/tags/opendtect/</link>
    <description>Recent content in opendtect on WM Seismic Solutions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://waynegm.github.io/tags/opendtect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First Release of Python Bindings to OpendTect</title>
      <link>https://waynegm.github.io/blog/opendtect-python-bindings-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waynegm.github.io/blog/opendtect-python-bindings-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 6.6.8 release of the wmPlugins includes a Python module, &lt;strong&gt;wmodpy&lt;/strong&gt;, to access OpendTect survey and well information. The &lt;strong&gt;odpy&lt;/strong&gt;
module already included with OpendTect uses a C++ command line application to interact with the OpendTect data structures. Each
request for data by the &lt;strong&gt;odpy&lt;/strong&gt; API incurs the overhead of starting this application and the writing and reading of the information as
an ascii data stream. The &lt;strong&gt;wmodpy&lt;/strong&gt; module, however, is a direct binding to the OpendTect C++ code so Python is directly reading from
the in-memory representation of the data. Data access with the &lt;strong&gt;wmodpy&lt;/strong&gt; module should be much faster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Jupyter_Lab with OpendTect</title>
      <link>https://waynegm.github.io/blog/jupyterlab-python-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waynegm.github.io/blog/jupyterlab-python-setup/</guid>
      <description>Fixing the kernel.json file for OpendTect Python The Jupyter architecture uses &amp;ldquo;kernel.json&amp;rdquo; files to identify a Jupyter kernel. If you have installed OpendTect and installed and selected one of the OpendTect ML Python environments in the Python Settings dialog, you can use the following command sequences on Linux and Windows to show a list of available Jupyter kernels. Open a console window (press Ctrl-T with the cursor in the OpendTect window) and enter the following depending on your system:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Visual Studio Code with OpendTect</title>
      <link>https://waynegm.github.io/blog/vscode-python-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waynegm.github.io/blog/vscode-python-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I show you how to set up and use the free &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; editor with OpendTect for interactive
computation using Python Jupyter Notebooks. If you have installed the OpendTect Machine Learning Python environments you can
create and edit Python Jupyter Notebooks using Visual Studio Code without modifying the installed environment provided VS Code is run from within
OpendTect. The approach described in this post might assist users in strictly controlled IT settings get up and running using Jupyter Notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
